Lee Colleton

<lee@colleton.net>

206.369.5391

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced System Administrator focused on monitoring, storage, backup and disaster recovery who has worked as both the sole sysadmin for a small animation company and as part of a global team at a 50,000+ employee corporation. Power-user and administrator of Linux systems for over 20 years.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Automation (Ansible, Puppet) * Scripting (Bash, Python, Go) * Security (ssh, GPG)
IT infrastructure services (DHCP, DNS, TFTP, PXE, NFS, HTTP)
Monitoring (Nagios) * Storage / SAN (NetApp) * Backup systems * Disaster Recovery
Specifying, building and provisioning hardware & virtual machines (VMware)
Cloud productivity apps (Microsoft Office 365 / Google G-Suite)

EXPERIENCE

Freelance consulting - Self employed

Seattle, Washington: August 2018 - September 2019

IT Systems Engineer - ExtraHop

Seattle, Washington: January 2018 - August 2018

Worked on a small team of engineers supporting the operations and infrastructure of the company. Performed hardware and software maintenance and upgrades. Served on the helpdesk escalation and 24/7 oncall rotation.

System Administrator - Google

Seattle, Washington: January 2006 - July 2014

Initially worked as the third IT Field Technician in Kirkland, Washington which was Google's first engineering office outside of Mountain View. I provided direct support to Google engineers as we grew the office to hundreds of employees between multiple campuses. In 2007 I transferred to the Systems Operations (sysops) group and worked first on the monitoring team then on corporate data storage and backup systems until July of 2014. My team practiced Agile development for our services. I have designed, specified and deployed hardware and software throughout Google's global offices.

System Administrator - Tooned In

Seattle, Washington: 2003 - 2005

Managed the workstations and servers of a computer game design company. Handled network administration, deployed and upgraded systems, performed technical support.

Nuclear Reactor Operator, Submarines - United States Navy

San Diego, California: April 1997 – April 2003

Served aboard the USS Houston (SSN-713) qualified up through Shutdown Reactor Operator, Battery Charging Electrician and ship's SCUBA diver. Auxiliary duties included administration of Windows NT and UNIX systems on shipboard LAN. Completed one WESTPAC tour and operated during reactor refueling in the PSNS shipyard at Bremerton, Washington ensuring worker safety during complex overhaul.

Volunteer Experience & Causes:

Low-carbon transportation advocate - Seattle Electric Vehicle Assn. (Electric Auto Assn. chapter) 2007 – Present

Educated and advocated for electrified transportation at the city, state, and national level.

Operated social media accounts on behalf of the club to advance de-carbonization of transport.

Advanced legislation and policy changes including public and workplace charging.

Researched new technology, particularly privacy & security impacts of networked vehicles.

co-founder - Seattle Privacy Coalition

April 2013 – Present

Organized and advocated for privacy issues in the city of Seattle and the state of Washington concerning UAVs, surveillance cameras, warrantless bulk data collection and regarding other technologies that impact individual privacy or enhance institutional transparency.

Education & Certifications

Willits High School - diploma

Electronics Technician Apprenticeship School, Orlando, Florida

U.S. Naval Nuclear Power School, Orlando, Florida

- Received certification as Nuclear Electronics Technician NEC 3373
- U.S. Naval Diving and Salvage Training Center, Pearl Harbor, Hawaii:
 - Received certification as Scuba Diver NEC 5345

USS Houston SSN-713, San Diego and Bremerton homeports:

Qualified as Reactor Operator and Shutdown Reactor Operator

MTA: Windows Operating System Fundamentals - Certified 2019 CompTIA A+ - Certified 2019

I've held a Secret clearance & am an honorably discharged veteran of the U.S. Navy.

References available on request.